hello and welcome to this session on
what's new in copilot de toolkit for
business Central 2024 release Wave 2 my
name is Peter boring and with me today I
have Julia mulet and enrio jimyen time
flies and especially in the context of
AI and co-art it's already a year ago
that we introduced a co-pilot developer
toolkit allowing Al developers a quick
and convenient way to tap into the Asher
open AI service using Al code and bring
generative co-pilot experiences to their
extensions in a consistent way with the
AA module in the system application The
Prompt dialogue UI uh sample code as
well as
guidance and in this code Focus session
you will learn more about the
enhancements to the developer uh toolkit
we'll present uh some new capabilities
uh that we are shipping in this release
and we will also revisit the sample app
uh showing an endtoend uh flow of
building a co-pilot feature using some
of these new
capabilities however while the session
includes some recap of how to build
co-pilot features in business Central it
builds on previous releases and thus if
this area is completely new to you then
I highly recommend that you view some of
those prior um sessions either before or
after uh this session and for your
convenience you can find the links to
these other uh sessions in the
description
below so let's continue with the
enhancements in this release uh the
first addition to the co-pilot developer
toolkit um is about co-pilot actions in
2024 release way 1 the developer tools
introduced uh these co-pilot prompt
actions a new way to drive attention to
co-pilot capabilities in your
extensions so a prompt action is a
standard action which is rendered with
greater prominence on the page such as
in a floating bar uh and is connected to
the co-pilot brand in the first
iteration business Central supported
copilot prompt actions on list list part
worksheet and standard dialogue page
types and to cater for more co-pilot
experiences and address partner feedback
we're now introducing support for
co-pilot prompt actions on additional
page types C document and list page uh
page types um we ourselves are using
this uh in the bank reconciliation uh
co-pilot now the required Al code uh to
to build this follows the same model as
when adding c-pod prompt actions to list
pages so as an example here we have
added four co-art prompt actions um to
the customer card via a page extension
where two of the co-pilot prompt actions
are listed in a group and we can see how
the actions uh to to or to do this we
see that we can add actions to the
prompting group uh that represents the
copil prompt actions and uh to group we
can provide a nested group in the
prompting area for the um for the nested
prompt
actions the second new feature in the
co-pilot developer toolkit is the
ability to display errors and warning
and messages directly within the
co-pilot prompt dialogues so users
learning to work with co-pilot often
needs simple and effective feedback loop
to help them experiment experiment and
make the uh most out of their AI powered
assistant and so um co-pilot features
that displays a prompt dialogue can now
show errors and messages directly inside
of the dialogue and while the prompt
dialogues aren't intended for
conversational EXP experiences the
integrated feedback keeps users focused
on the dialogue without
distractions now
um the the errors and messages thrown by
the code in co-pilot prompt dialogues
will now basically surface directly
inside the dialogue rather than in a
separate uh popup and so there's no
additional work required uh by the
developer to enable this
functionality and we support both the
classic uh the classic dialog error and
a dialog message as well as the newer
error info uh
patterns there are some behavioral
details uh though compared to sort of
the the normal um pop-up dialogues that
um f first of all if the code throws
multiple messages only the last will be
shown H we will indicate that more were
thrown but only the last will be shown
also uh we do not support line breaks in
uh in the inline experience in cop pilot
uh prompt dialoges and just like with
the normal sort of flow for errors and
messages if an error is thrown any sub
subsequent messages will not uh be uh be
rendered then a smaller but important
user experience Improvement uh to The
Prompt dialog is the support to resize
columns this is provided as part of a
general support uh across business
Central so that um you can now change uh
column sizes uh cross uh uh Pages cross
list
Pages um this applies per user and per
page including the prompt dialogue and
it does not require personalization uh
permission so you can actually have
users do that without being allowed to
do any kind of
personalization then we have some
improvements to function calling so
function calling is a way to extract and
delegate AI tasks to specialized tools
uh that could be for instance be
providing a weather forecast for a
certain location date and time and so if
you have a prompt that asks for that you
can extract that being sort of a
something to fulfill and call A
specialized function to return that and
if you want to learn more about uh
function calling we had a prior um
launch event session on extending
copilot using Al code um you will also
find a link to this in the description
uh for this session
now in this release uh we have unblocked
parallel function calling so that the
model returns uh the tool calls in one
response and that optimizes the round
trips to the llm uh you can now also use
a new Al interface uh for your functions
um again I have provided a link here but
we will also have that in the
description uh below both of these we
will talk more about later in this
session in the in the code uh part
then um we of course have Telemetry and
uh for the last many many years uh we're
giving you a lot of telemetry options
because Telemetry is really good at
getting insights about uh how your
product is being used and now you can
actually also get Telemetry events uh
from the AI module uh optic sent to your
application insights right so that
allows isvs to track feature usage for
their co-pilot features built with a
co-pilot developer toolkit um so the AI
module in system app and it will use the
application insid connection string that
is defined in the app. Json manifest uh
of the calling app or extension right
and so the way that you enable this is
that you of course have to provide an
app uh insights Connection in your
extension uh as well as you also have to
do a little bit of coding on uh setting
up the Telemetry logger and for both of
these things I added some links and you
will find those in the description
below now once you have this Telemetry
enabled for your co-al features you of
course want to um to react on them or
see the insides and you can either
monitor that yourself or you can take
advantage of the powerbi app that we
have available for isvs where you can
for instance use that to track feature
usage or a feature uptake or even uh
issues or errors with your features from
uh
Telemetry then as we talked about uh
Partners can build their thirdparty
co-pilot features quickly uh in business
Central using the co-pilot developer
toolkit uh the current approach is then
for the partner to bring their own
self-managed and dedicated AI resources
right so basically bring their own as
open AI um account right and so we we
are on track to enable managed AI
resources so that you do not have to
bring your own account uh or for that
matter track usage or cost yourself
manage the deployment scaling Etc so
that would actually offload uh a lot of
task from you so you can focus on just
your co-pilot feature and uh these manag
AI resources they are currently in
private preview uh we expect a public
preview to open in the end or Al of
2024 and if you want to learn more about
these managed AI resources Sandy had a
as part of a session in the previous
launch event he talked about this uh
again I provided a link and you will
find it in the descriptions uh below so
these were the improvements uh to the
co-pilot developer toolkit in this
release so Julia can you show how we
quickly can build a copil feature using
some of these new capabilities of course
we will build a eilot extension in
business Central that will suggest as a
project so what exactly will we build
today we will build suggest project with
co-pilot a copilot action on Project's
page where the user inputs description
of a needed project copell will generate
that project proposal and some suggested
tasks and we'll learn how to display
error and messages within the prompt
dialect something that Peter already
mentioned the compiler's role in the
extension will as I mentioned generate
the project and tasks as well as use two
functions and select which one needs to
be used
automatically before I go straight to uh
Visual Studio code I'll first show you
what will be the end product um of our
coding today as you can see here I'm
already on the project page and you can
see our copile action that's is draft
with copilot so let's see what it does a
prompt dialog opens uh where we ask the
user to describe the project they want
to create if that extension looks
somewhat familiar to you it is a more
concise version of the sample app we
already had uh in our BCT Tech uh
repository but there's some new things
first of all uh let's see the new
display of error messages as now if the
input is empty will not generate but
display uh a message an error message to
the user to describe uh the project they
want to generated so let's see that in
action I'll use one of our prompt guides
to create a campaign for tray
research and let's see what kopila can
do as you can see it provides us with
short project description the customer
name that we have provided and some
suggested tasks as part of the job
structure and as part of the
improvements of the prompt dialogue you
can also now
resize the
column perfect so let's get to coding
this
extension I am now in visual studio and
I have prepared for myself some code
Snippets uh to expedite uh this demo uh
you'll see that Cod the code snippet are
not part of the sample app however you
in the repository you'll find the whole
sample app with all the C code provided
so how do we start building EOP pilot
extension in business Central well we
are providing a new compilot capability
of course so we will need to extend uh
extend that uh inum copil capability
having our own suggest a
project then we need to register that
capability uh on install or on update
here I have on install so if the copilot
capability is not yet
registered I
then register it here using the copilot
capability code unit perfect so our
capability is registered already then we
go to extending the page where we want
uh our copilot action to show so here we
are extending job list or project
list and in actions in area prompting uh
we can add our own copilot action that
you have already already seen in the
demo great so we have registered
capability created an extension Now we
move on to creating a prompt dialogue
page so here we have a prompt dialog
page and in the layout we have two
important areas The Prompt area and the
content area in the prompt area this is
where your user will Pro uh will provide
input
so we put
a field that will allow just
that then the content area as you know
is where we present what copilot has
generated so here we'll input Fields uh
that we saw there like uh customer name
project short description and the
subport that is a repeater of the job
tasks so we now have the frame on where
where we will display both the input
port and the output for your user to
interact with in the dialogue then in
the demo you saw me use one of our
prompt guides uh I think I picked create
a campaign and you can add your own
prompt guides to your copilot extensions
to guide your users into what they can
do then you also saw some uh actions in
the system actions area such as generate
and then generate this is where we
trigger uh the magic the compilot part
of the behavior of our extension so we
want to generate that project we have a
suggested job generate proposal code
unit and there uh we call
copilot so here in running generation
you can see that we open the progress
dialogue with our custom text that's how
you can customize the uh message that is
displayed while the co-pilot is
working set user prompt reset the
previous output that we had
and have three attempts uh to run the uh
generate proposal code unit and get the
results if there's an error we would
display an error but we saw a different
error when there was no uh
input uh that's because here we can also
provide any other messages and errors uh
that we
need simply as if you were generating a
standard error or a standard message in
business cental
great so that's a uh that's a frame that
we have to generate that proposal but
now let's dive
into the actual parts of interacting of
running uh our co-pilot functions uh and
generating our proposal enri could you
take us through it yes of course thank
you juliia so let's dig a bit deeper
into how the actual calls to aure open
AI work um on a lower level so here you
see that I have the actual core of this
extension where I am generating the job
proposal and as you can see it's just
like some 20 lines of code but you need
to have of course the right lines of
code so let's go through them so the
first thing you need to do is you need
to set uh authorization to the asure
open AI code unit so in my case I am
using this manage resource authorization
as Peter mentioned before we are now
running this prr program uh with
selected partners that is going to open
up to every partner uh very soon to use
U manage resources from Microsoft so
that's what I'm using here um uh you
also have the option of using your own
aure open AI subscription in that case
there is a slightly different syntax you
need to use which is um shown here but
in my case I will just keep this
commented and use the manage resource
instead you need some more setup on the
uh asure open AI General level so for
example here we need to specify which
capability we are using Julia showed you
earlier how to register a new capability
in the system this is used for multiple
Purp
for example for tracking but also so
that admins can choose on a more fine
grain level which co-pilot capabilities
they want active in their system or
not you can also fine tune some more
parameters for example the max tokens or
the temperature you don't need to do
that um in simple cases but if you want
some more complicated scenario or if you
want copilot to be more or less creative
when it replies then uh you will need to
customize those and then what we're
using here is the copilot chat
completion endpoint which which means
you need to add some chat messages so
here as you can see I have some system
message which is basically telling asure
open a what is the uh main task to
fulfill and then we have a user message
which is the actual user
prompt as Julia mentioned this sample is
similar to the one we had already in BC
with the difference that instead of
having some long and rather complicated
XML parsing then we're instead using
tools so tools are this very cool
feature in asure open AI that we Al
exposed in our toolkit which allows you
basically to specify U uh like client
side if you want or like um alite Plugin
or function that you can make available
for the llm um so in this case we have
two functions or tools that we're adding
they are called Suggest job create job
and uh create job task so now copilot
knows that they can call these two to
basically create a new job or a new job
task we uh are also exposing some new
options for you to set the tool Behavior
what does this mean with the tool invoke
preference you can tell our Al toolkit
that you want the uh tools to be
automatically invoked when copilot tells
the toolkit that he wants to invoke some
Tool uh there are other options here for
example you can set it to manual that
means it's going to be on you as the
developer to actually call your tool
once copilot tells you that that's the
tool he wants to call we also have this
tool Choice which can limit which tools
pilot can call so you can just tell
copilot look there's multiple tools but
I just want you to call one of them for
example um it might make sense for
actually you can also set it to none so
you can just tell co- pilot look there
are some tools but for this specific
moment I don't want you to call them u
in most of the cases auo is the option
you want but um you might want to F tune
this as
well and then finally generate chat
completion is where all of the co-pilot
generation happens and then you will
just get back a response as you can see
at the endend here of my function I am
getting back from the function code unit
the
result so um this is U interesting but
let's actually see how like what does
this mean to get back the result so let
me switch back to um the actual function
now as you can see on top here of the
file I am implementing this new
interface which Peter mentioned as well
before which is this aoi function
interface that is in the AL toolkit
so this interface contains three
functions which are get prompt execute
and get name you need to implement all
three of them for your function to be
recognized by the AL toolkit and then
you can of course have more functions as
if uh as a normal code unit so in my
case my suggest uh job or create job
function wants uh get job um specific
procedure to get back the result but the
other one I have which is the job task
will need for example to get out the job
task and for your own specific
implementation you you might need
different functions and that's totally
fine as long as you have the three that
are mandated by the interface let's have
a slightly deeper look on how those
functions look like so the get name is
very straightforward you just need to
tell copilot what's the name of your
function the execute will depend very
much on your implementation in my case
I'm just basically uh iterating through
the temporary record and inserting
whatever copilot tells me to insert but
what I think what's more interesting is
the get prompt function uh and
you this is where basically you are
defining the function as a Json object
and you are giving that to copilot there
is a specific um format you need to use
here you can easily find it either in
our samples or in the documentation but
as you can see here I am basically
giving copilot a tool and the function
definition with its own parameters so
copilot will know which properties needs
to be defined when it tries to call this
function so let's summarize what you
just saw in this session so you saw some
copilot actions available in the uh new
page types for example in card Pages as
well as in list Pages you also saw from
Julia's demo how to display error
messages directly inside prom dialogue
as well as um normal messages
informational for the user and that's
just by using the built-in message and
error functions Julia also showed how to
resize columns in the prom dialog that's
also a nice new feature in the client
and also Peter showed you how you can
get in application insights some more
Telemetry about how your users use
compiled
features I showed you some fun function
calling and how you can achieve um like
some new cleaner and nicer code using
functions and tools and and that's all
so now you know how to build your
extension from ground app so what do you
need to do now well first of all make
sure you go and watch the previous
videos on the copil developer to Kit so
all of these is still current we have of
course new updates but you um you still
want to make sure you watch the uh
introductory videos we also have of
course docs on the cilo toolkit so make
sure you have a look at those as well as
the samples we have on BCTC you can see
the links on screen but also they will
be in the description of this
video so now you're ready to build some
awesome copilot features for our
customers also make sure as we mentioned
before multiple times to keep an eye on
the public preview for manage resources
that's coming later this year and you
really don't want to miss
that that's all we have for you today
thank you for your attention